<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Shuhei A. Horiguchi</title>
    <link>https://s-horiguchi.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Shuhei A. Horiguchi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://s-horiguchi.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AIR for Human</title>
      <link>https://s-horiguchi.github.io/projects/air/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://s-horiguchi.github.io/projects/air/</guid>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence Research for Human (人工知能研究会 / AIR) is a community for artificial intelligence research led by students and young researchers. We received the Open Innovation Award from the Minister of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology. 第４回 日本オープンイノベーション大賞 内閣総理大臣賞等</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://s-horiguchi.github.io/projects/programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://s-horiguchi.github.io/projects/programming/</guid>
      <description>I organized a programming tutorial for scientists with two other members of WINGS-ABC.
Tutorial Webpage
The goal of this tutorial was to introduce a variety of know-how which is very common in expert programmers but not known among scientists. We covered the following topics:
Sharing the code Environment setup (pip, pyenv, pipenv, Docker, VSCode) Parameter search and logging (mlflow) Version control Readability of the code Linter, Type checker Test, Unit test Reproducibility of Jupyter notebook We also prepared sample codes for a deeper understanding of our tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theory of The Immune System</title>
      <link>https://s-horiguchi.github.io/projects/immune_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://s-horiguchi.github.io/projects/immune_learning/</guid>
      <description>Understanding the Immune system with Learning Theory.
Publications:
ArXiv 2022 ICMMA 2021 Annual Meeting of JSMB2021 Master thesis Annual Meeting of JSMB2020 Workshop on Theoretical Biology Q-bio Caravan 2019 Annual Meeting of JSMB </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OUXT Polaris</title>
      <link>https://s-horiguchi.github.io/projects/ouxt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://s-horiguchi.github.io/projects/ouxt/</guid>
      <description>OUXT Polaris is a team for the Maritime RobotX Challenge. I was the team leader on 2018 Challenge at Honolulu. We received judge&amp;rsquo;s special award. We were funded by Leave a Nest Co., Ltd. : The Nippon Foundation Marine Engineering Award (第40回リバネス研究費 日本財団海洋工学賞), and seven companies. We were also</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
